Reagan Kieti Munyao Software Engineer

Phone: +254719395844

Email: reagankieti@gmail.com

GitHub: https://github.com/reagankieti

Linked-In: https://www.linkedin.com/in/reagankieti
Portfolio website: https://reagankieti.github.io

Profile Summary

Software engineer with 3+ years of work experience in full stack application development, web user interface creation, USSD and SMS services, web services development, testing and establishing system improvements. Ready and willing to learn and partake upcoming technologies.

Education Background

- Sep 2014- Oct 2018 BSc. Computer Science Chuka University, 2nd Class Upper Division.
- 2010-2013 Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education Kathiani Boys High School, A –

Areas of Expertise

- Software development using Java, Python and PHP.
- PostgreSQL & MySQL schema design and implementation.
- Web services integration with mobile applications.
- RESTful API design
- Data analysis and presentation using NumPy, Matplotlib, Pandas, Python and Jaspersoft.
- Source code management & version control using Git & SVN
- Knowledge in Mastery of Office Suite (MS Office, MS Excel and PowerPoint)
- Knowledge of design using Figma (wireframes) and graphic design using canva, adobe illustrator and photoshop.
- Content management system development using WordPress.
- Knowledge of Cloud Computing services for Azure, AWS and Huawei.
- Knowledge in Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning.

Work Experience

Aug 2021 to Oct 2021: Software Engineer – SMART PEOPLE AFRICA - Under Presidential

DigiTalent Talent Program

- Technical support for Smart Revenue Water billing system for 20 companies in Kenya.
- Documenting and training the support staff the solution for problem raised.
- Working with ERP Microsoft Dynamics **Achievements**
- Support and sorting Clients SPA Website

Oct 2020 to Aug 2021: Software Developer – KENYA SCHOOL OF GOVERNMENT - Under

Presidential DigiTalent Talent Program

Key Functions

- User Interface design for Web applications
- Design, development and configuration of dashboards.
- Responding and resolving of issues raised by staff and participants.
- Convert user stories to systems requirements.

Achievements

- Developed Staff Training Feedback System <u>Staff Website Link</u>
- Maintained School Systems Microsoft Dynamics, School Website
- Designed UI/UX for Development of Educational Content for DigiSchool. (For ICT Authority)

Feb 2020 to Jun 2020: Software Developer Apprentice – Makueni County

Key Functions

- Developing back-end solutions for apps.
- Design and develop User interfaces for dashboards and forms.
- Maintaining web applications, ensuring up-time and dependability
- Working with the Senior Developer to ensure that web applications developed are intuitive and user friendly
- Providing technical support to users when require.

Achievements

- Developed Makueni Youth Empowerment platform user interface website link
- Aided in development of Makueni ECDE and education management systems. website link

Jun 2018 to Sep 2019: ICT support - Zuhura Group of Companies

Key Functions

- Networking and Installation of Software and Printers
- Graphic Designing with Adobe Illustrator, Photoshop
- Customer support and troubleshooted any technology failure for the Company.
- Training entry level Employees and Staff on Company's Technologies.

Jun 2017 to Sept 2017: ICT Attaché, Kenya Civil Aviation Authority

Kev Functions

- Troubleshooting and maintenance of the network.
- Installation of IP telephones in the county offices.
- Installations and support of office PC.
- Help desk support to customers.
- Data recovery and back-up.
- Installing and configuring printers
- Rolling out of virus, running, updating and keeping anti-virus programs and data.

Achievements

• Took part in designing and production of Identity Cards for KCAA Staff.

Training and Certification

- Managing Successful Project with Prince2 -July, 2021- Learnovate Technologies
- HCIA -AI Certificate March 2021 to April 2021 Huawei
- HCIA Machine Learning Certificate March 2021 to April 2021 Huawei
- HCIA Cloud Computing Certification March 2021 to April 2021- Huawei
- Basic Digital Skills Training February 2021- eMobilis Mobile Training Academy
- Microsoft Azure Fundamentals AZ-900 May -July 2020- Andela Learning Community.
- #BuildForSDG Challenge 2020 Certificate of Completion Cohort I Facebook Circle Developers and Andela

Referees

Mr. John Kirimi - Kenya School of Government, Head of ICT Dept john.mwenda@ksg.ac.ke
Tel:0726206007

Mr. Stephen Mbuvi – Makueni County – Senior ICT Officer mbuvi.steve@makueni.go.ke Tel:0729441829

 $\begin{array}{l} Mr.\ Victor\ Peter-\ Smart\ People\ Africa-Technical\ Manager\\ \underline{victor@spa-limited.com}\\ \underline{Tel:0716177880} \end{array}$